# Charles Wu

**UX** Designer & Developer

1-647-767-6126 ☐ charleswu.ca ☐ hi@charleswu.ca ☐

### **Summary**

A versatile and agile user-experience designer & developer, adept in research, planning, and converting user needs into product requirements. He is efficient at converting designs into tangible results through the means of prototypes, animation, and code.

## Experience

### **UX** Developer

Sep 2016 - Present

CareerJSM, Toronto

- Designed and implemented prototypes for stakeholders to demonstrate new Job Search Management application features
- Conducted web accessibility audit and performed necessary design and code updates to meet WCAG Level-A requirements
- Planned and implemented user testing sessions to validate features

#### **UX** Developer

Aug 2015 - Jul 2016

DIVE Networks, Toronto

- Led company UX training sessions to enhance product direction
- Optimized visual content for web and TV displays, factoring in content size, speed, and viewer distance
- Created user personas and use-cases to enhance functionality and usability for key audiences
- Developed an automation script to isolate anomalies by analyzing visual differences

#### **UX Designer & Developer**

Jan 2015 – Jun 2015

Crowd Curio, Waterloo

- Improved user engagement by testing and optimizing different layouts, and through added gamification elements
- Created information architecture maps, wireframes, and prototypes

### **UX** Designer

Jun 2014 – Aug 2014

McKinsey Digital Labs, New York

- Produced wireframes, storyboards, and mock-ups, making use of user research and user-centered design principles
- Consulted with clients to translate business requirements into feature sets and designs

#### iOS Developer & Product Designer

Jan 2013 – Apr 2013

AlphaBroder (formerly Ash City), Richmond Hill

- Independently managed, designed, and developed a mobile catalog and ordering app, from conception to delivery within a 4 month deadline
- Organized and led one-on-one user testing sessions

#### **Skills**

**UX:** User Research, User Testing, Wireframing, Information Architecture Design, Prototyping (Adobe CS, Sketch, Axure), Web Accessibility (WCAG 2.0)

**Dev:** HTML, CSS (SCSS, BEM), JS (Vanilla, Ember), Python, Java, Git

#### Education

Bachelors of Applied Science (BASc), University of Waterloo

2010 - 2015

Systems Design Engineering, Option in Management Science

# **Projects and Interests**

#### **Projects**

- Curio-X: Designed and optimized a citizen science and gamification project to digitally catalog images
- BufferBox (acquired by Google): Led a team of 3 designers and marketers
- Proxima: Fabricated and tested a glove to wirelessly transfer data via gestures
- Focus: Built and published a study tool
- InFit: Developed a fitness tracking app to process biometric data

#### Volunteer

- Engineering Society Class Rep for Systems Design 2015
- Orientation Week Director 2013-2014

#### Recreation

In my free time, I enjoy rock climbing, photography, volleyball, biking, cooking, and traveling. I also work on my Android app, which uses Al and machine learning to improve personal schedules.